<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shan Sun</title>
    <link>https://shan.tax/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shan Sun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Shan Sun</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shan.tax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Personal Website for Free</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/posts/building-a-personal-website-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/posts/building-a-personal-website-for-free/</guid>
      <description>📎Why? Over the years, I set up various blog sites for myself and others using existing services such as Squarespace and WordPress. This year, I want to do something different - making the build process itself a learning journey. It&amp;rsquo;s a good time to do it because of a vast amount of excellent free open-source software available and plenty of tutorials/videos around.
📖How? I have some experience with writing in markdown, working with Python and Git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/about/</guid>
      <description>⬇️ shansun-public-1.pdf
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology for Transfer Pricing</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/posts/technology-for-transfer-pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/posts/technology-for-transfer-pricing/</guid>
      <description>My tax technology journey starts with transfer pricing (&amp;ldquo;TP&amp;rdquo;) given much of the TP work involves tailored data analytics and visualisation. For technical correspondence with tax authorities, I also provided econometric based statistical analyses. For multinational companies, TP is a highly visible area of tax with governments agreeing to exchange data and hence many potential technology applications. It is therefore desirable to establish a modern data-driven TP management in-house with a systematic overarching design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Governance in Tax</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/posts/machine-learning-governance-in-tax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/posts/machine-learning-governance-in-tax/</guid>
      <description>Many areas of tax incorporated machine learning, but it is not a silver bullet. What are the potential risks of adopting a machine learning approach to replace manual efforts and how could we mitigate such risks? This blog post discusses some governance measures I put in place to address these questions.
Common applications The most frequent machine learning application I came across in tax falls into the category of classification prediction modelling, typically includes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeking into the Giants: Analysing the ADIMA Database</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/posts/peeking-into-the-giants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/posts/peeking-into-the-giants/</guid>
      <description>This blog was first published on medium.com and Analytics Vidhya News Bytes
This blog examines the Analytical Database of Individual Multinational Enterprises (MNEs) and their Affiliates (ADIMA) dataset from OECD to understand the structure and presence of the top 100 MNEs of our time across the world.
Background Visibility of information on Multinational Enterprises (MNEs) has been limited at best despite their significant and growing importance in our daily lives as well as public policy area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualisation in Tax</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/posts/data-visualisation-in-tax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/posts/data-visualisation-in-tax/</guid>
      <description>Tax and finance teams use an excessive amount of dashboards. The contents are often limited to simple bar charts and histograms. However, tax data is multi-dimensional which means the simple two-dimensional representations may no longer be sufficient.
I believe modern data visualisation in tax should increasingly serve the users with more depth in that it could allow users to:
 interact with data, explore and tell a story from the data, and/or; directly enable an action point from the visualisation  I explain this thinking with an example in transfer pricing below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills for Future Tax Professionals</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/posts/skills-for-future-tax-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/posts/skills-for-future-tax-professionals/</guid>
      <description>*Some updates on this subject are here.
I often hear tax professionals around me wondering what skills our profession should have under the rapid progression of data and technology. The confusion, or more accurately the dilemma seems to be antagonistic option of resourcing established data scientists who adapt to the tax problem domain, or to expect tax professionals to learn data analytics, or even deeper.
I suspect similar questions are on many non-tech industry professionals’ mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBCR Analysis</title>
      <link>https://shan.tax/posts/cbcr-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shan.tax/posts/cbcr-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Background OECD&amp;rsquo;s BEPS project Action 13 provides a template for multinational enterprises (&amp;ldquo;MNEs&amp;rdquo;) to report annually and for each tax jurisdiction in which they do business the information set out therein. This report is called the Country-by-Country Report (&amp;ldquo;CBCR&amp;rdquo;). The CBCR template requires two tables of MNEs&#39; financial and operational information.
Exploratory data analysis In the first year of submitting CBCR, I wanted to use Python instead of Excel to see how one may get more insights from the data collected in CBCR.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
